Lenia Margariti

UX/UI Developer

Creative and innovative UX/UI designer and developer with great capacity in composite and analytical thinking, research and problem-solving. Solid IT and programming skills, knowledge of industry standard web technologies and Agile methodology. Experienced in interdisciplinary collaboration and stakeholder management across various sectors.

+44(0)7517084859 lenia.margariti@gmail.com LinkedIn: leniamargaritis www.leniam.com

Current Employment

Cosmote / Digital Transformation Analyst

February 2018 - Present, Athens, Greece

Based in the IT Digitalization & Innovation team at Cosmote Telecom. The service design team improves current products and brings new concepts of services utilizing emerging technologies in order to enhance digital transformation in the company, following design thinking and a user-centered design approach.

Key responsibilities;

- Successfully translating new product concepts into user flows, wireframes, mockups and prototypes.
- Facilitating communications with startups, academia and other stakeholders.
- Redesign of main Journeys and UI development (HTML/CSS) of Internal Ideation Platform, contributing to milder user flows and increasing engagement through gamification.
- Design and front-end development for Oculus and Hololens in Unity (C#) and in JS frameworks (Aframe, WebAR) for the AR versions of Cosmote App.
- Redesigning the UI for the mobile AR version of Cosmote Smart Home.
- Development in Python for human-Robot Interaction project using Softbank Pepper for customer experience. Development of Voice Interface applications integrating various APIs
- Contributing to in European Research projects on interactive technologies as a design consultant
- Organising and participating in Hackathons and Tech Events as a UI/UX mentor.

Professional Training

CodeBase / CodeClan Digital Academy

September 2017 - February 2018, Edinburgh, UK

SCQF level 8 - Professional Development Award in Software Development

4-month intensive programming course delivered according to OOP design principles and Agile methodology;

- Comprised by 3-week iterative module learning-blocks and 1 week project-Sprints.
- Following a test-driven approach to development
- \bullet Focusing on industry-stan¬dard web technologies such as REST, HTML5, CSS3, SQL, JAVA, Ruby, JS and React.

Projects:

- "Money Cashboard for Millenials" / RESTful smart budgeting web application with Ruby's Sinatra framework and Postgress SQL DB: Github link
- "My ToDos" / Native application developed in Java Android Studio and SQLite according to OOP design principles. Emphasis in mobile UX/UI design: Github link
- Front-end web applications with vanilla JavaScript integrating APIs: Github link

UX Fundamentals

Introduction in UX and UI development essentials: User/Market Research, Personas, Wireframing, Prototyping, User tasting, UX strategy/product design.

Skills

Design:

2D graphics • Concept Sketches • Wireframes • Mokups

2D

Adobe Suite CS6: Photoshop, Illustrator, InDesign, After Effects • Sketch • Balsamic • Affinity Designer

3D

3Ds Max • SketchUp • Blender Rhino& Grasshopper

Other Utilities

Unity • Aframe • Three.JS • Blender4Web • 3D modeling and fabrication

Prototyping:

User flows and User Journeys
• InVision • Figma • UxPin

Programming:

Languages

HTML • CSS • JS • Jquerry • Ruby • Python • Java • C#

Frameworks/Libraries

Sinatra • Node • React

Databases

PostgreSQL• MongoDB

Coding Fundamentals

OOP -SOLID principles •
Testing - TDD • DB design
• Git version control •
AJAX / DOM manipulation

Employment History

Urban Transcrips / Designer and Research Assistant

May 2017 - present, London, UK (distance collaboration)

Member of Citizen Engagement Team.

- Researching Digital Tools for Public Engagement.
- Designing and developing interactive maps integrating social media and google maps API.

PlastiqHaus Design Studio, TechCube / Architectural / 3D Designer

August 2015 - May 2017, Edinburgh, UK

Designer in a start up Design consultancy specialising in Architecture, Visualization and Immersive Design.

- Development of Concept Designs, 3D models, Visualizations and graphics for web services for the real estate market.
- Key responsibilities included; Architectural Design, Modeling&Rendering, Product Research.
- Team Coordination, liaising with Consultants.
- VR simulations in Unity.

Academic Education

The University of Edinburgh / MSc Urban Strategies and Design Grade: 7.2/10.0

September 2014 - August 2015, Edinburgh, UK

School of Architecture, ESALA & courses from School of Design, Design informatics

Focus on Smart Cities and communities, e-gov and Urban Informatics. My dissertation was a case study on a digital service exhange platfrom. My target was to add knowledge on the improvement of Digital Citizen Services within the sphere of Sharing Economy - Grade: 7.8/10.0

BA&MSc in Architecture / Aristotle University of Thessaloniki Grade: 8.70/10.0

September 2006 - September 2013, Thessaloniki, Greece

Interests in Computer Aided Design, Digital Fabrication, Modelling and Visualisation.

MSc in Architecture, TH Koeln - Exchange Semester in Cologne

September 2010- February 2011

Licended Architect, Greece / Registered Architect UK

February 2017

Publications

Margariti, E., Onabulu, T., 'Decentralised Autonomous Housing', Contribution to the Workshop 'New Value Transactions: Understanding and Designing for Distributed Autonomous Organisations' at DIS 2017: 'Designing Interactive Systems: Space, Place, Interface' International Conference.

Margariti, E., Travlou, P., 'Sharing within a city in crisis: Two ICTs-supported P2P economic networks in Thessaloniki, Northern Greece'. Proceedings of Hybrid City III Conference (2015), published in Int. J. of Electronic Governance.

Collaboration:

High level of preservance Attention to detail Organizing UX/UI trainings Effective in team work
Communicative Successful in deadline management and project Coordination Ability to learn new skills and technologies quickly

Research:

Design Thinking • Service Design • Product Research • Innovation • Emerging Technologies • HCI - HRI • AR/VR

Languages:

English / Fluent
German / Good B2
Greek / Native

Interests:

Sci-Fi lover • Outdoors • Bouldering • Yoga • Contemporary Dance